That was close.
真悬
God, I love the smell of
paintballs in the morning.
神呐 我爱死早上的彩弹味儿了
Yeah, still funny, Raj.
是啊 不过还是很滑稽 Raj
There's no way we can get to the ridge.
我们根本没法到山脊上去
The Chemistry Department
has us completely cut off.
化学部的家伙彻底断了我们的路
But what about the creek bed?
那河床那边呢?
The Pharmacology Department controls that, and
they're all hopped up on experimental steroids.
药理学部的家伙控制着呢
别忘了他们都吃了实验用的类固醇
That's it then. We're doomed.
那可好了 我们完了
I think the time has come to acknowledge
that we are paying the price for some of us
我觉得现在是该遭报应的时候了
failing to attend my Physics
Department paintball strategy meeting.
我们中的某些人可是没有
参加物理部的彩弹策略会议
I told you my mom has spider veins.
都跟你说了我妈得了蜘蛛静脉
I had to take her to the laser clinic.
我得带她去医院照激光
And I told you I wante
to see a doctor's note.
我也跟你说了让你把病例卡给我
We need a plan.
我们得拟定个计划
How about Operation Hammer of the Gods?
执行"上帝之锤"计划如何?
I forget. Which one
is Hammer of the Gods?
我都忘了 哪个是"上帝之锤"?
We hide behind the Dumpsters in the parking
lot and ambush people when they come to pee.
我们躲在停车场的垃圾堆旁
伏击那些来尿尿的家伙
No go. The Dumpsters are deep in
Astronomy Department territory.
不行 垃圾堆在天文部的大后方
That shouldn't be a problem.
Venus is up during the day.
那不成问题 白天金星不正亮着呢
They're probably just
all staring at the sky.
他们可能都在仰望天空呢
All right, what we need
now is a tactical retreat.
好吧 我们要来一次战术性撤退
Did you see the episode of Stargate
where they found themselves on a planet
你看过那集星际之门么?
他们发现自己正身处于一个
with a culture based loosely
on Earth's Athens and Sparta?
基于地球上的雅典和斯巴达
文明的行星之上
Not important.
那不重要
Leonard, Raj and I are going to
burst out the door and run away.
Leonard Raj 还有我一起冲出门去
Howard will cover us.
Howard来掩护我们
Why don't I run away and you cover me?
为什么不是我冲出去你们来掩护我?
Because you chose your
mother's veins over victory.
因为在胜利和你妈的蜘蛛静脉之间
你选择了后者
On three. One, two, three, go!
数到三 一 二 三 出发!
I had to take her! It's
almost bathing suit weather!
我没法不带她去! 夏天都快到了!
I surrender! Don't
shoot! They went that way!
我投降! 别开枪! 他们往那边跑了!
Howard, I'm on your team.
Howard 我是你队友
Oh, Leslie, thank God.
噢 Leslie 谢天谢地
Where's the rest of your squad?
你们队的其他人呢?
Ah, they left me here to die.
啊 他们丢下我一个人在这儿等死
What about yours?
你们队呢?
Dead, all of them.
都死了
Sorry.
抱歉
Don't be. It was friendly fire.
不必 都是我干的
They just wouldn't listen.
他们就是不听
Well, we're surrounded, so I
guess there's nothing for us to do
好吧 我们被包围了
我想除了在这儿等着被俘被杀
but wait to be captured or killed.
没什么其他事能干了
Hmm, that's the worst part, the waiting.
哼 等待是最不好玩的了
All the while knowing that there's a
paint pellet out there with your namen it.
一直想着外头有颗写着
自己名字的彩弹在等着
Yeah, the big wet ball of death.
没错 又大又湿 宣告你的死期
Kind of makes you feel
more alive, doesn't it?
倒是更能体会生的感觉 不是吗?
It kind of does.
确实有点
I say we make every moment count.
我说 我们不能虚度光阴
I agree.
同意
How exactly do we do that?
我们究竟该怎么做?
Howard, why aren't you covering us?
We're getting slaughtered out here!
Howard 你为啥不掩护我们?
我们被人屠杀了!
War is hell.
活受罪的战争
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=-
proudly presents
-=伊甸园美剧http://sfile.ydy.com=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=-
sync:咔肉肉
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=-
翻译: 饭特稀 penny
校对: penny
时间轴: 咔肉肉
双语:徐小帆
The Big Bang
Theory Season02 Episode16
天才理论传
第二季 第16集
Did you guys see the new budget
memo that went out this morning?
你们看见今晨出的预算备忘录了么?
Yeah, more cutbacks.
嗯 又削减了不少
Unacceptable.It baffles me why
they don't simply let some of you go
无法接受 我就想不通了
干嘛不干脆让你们中的某些人滚蛋
so that there's money
available for my research.
这样我的研究经费就有保障了
You know what baffles me, Sheldon?
你知道我想不通啥么 Sheldon?
Based on your academic record,
any number of things, I imagine.
基于你的学术记录
你想不通的事多了去了
- Hey, guys.
- Hey, Leslie.
- 嘿 你们好
- 嘿 Leslie
Howard, I got the approval for
the rapid prototyper you wanted.
Howard 你要的快速原型机
我替你批下来了
That's great, Leslie. Thanks.
真是太好了 Leslie 多谢
You scratch my back, I scratch yours.
你替我抓背 我当然要还你了
What was all that about?
那是怎么回事?
Oh, uh, no big deal. They gave Leslie
control of some unrestricted grant money.
噢 没什么 他们让Leslie掌管
一些非限制性基金
Yeah, okay, but what's with the back
- scratching and the meow!
那是没错 不过抓背还有"喵"是怎么回事!
I believe the back-scratching metaphor
generally describes a quid p quo situation
我想那个"抓背"的比喻
主要说的是相互报答
where one party provides goods or services to the
second party in compensation for a similar action.
一方提供货物或服务
另一方给予类似的回馈
Thank you.
谢谢侬
The meow, that sounded to
me like an African civet cat.
而那个"喵" 听上去像是种非洲灵猫
Are you done?
说完了没?
No.
还没
Despite what the name suggests,
the civet cat is not a true cat.
虽然名字里有个猫字
但灵猫并不是一种猫
Now I'm done.
这下说完了
You know what I'm thinking?
你知道我在想什么吗?
I'm thinking Howard wasn't
making a back-scratching metaphor.
我在想Howard的"抓背"并非是个比喻
I'm thinking there was some
actual scratching involved.
我想应该真的有抓才是
What about it, Howard?
你说呢 Howard?
Okay, I didn't want to say anything 'cause
I know you and Leslie have a little history.
好吧 我什么都不想说
因为你和Leslie有过那么一小段
I don't care about that.
这我倒是不在乎
Great, 'cause I've been
dying to say something.
太好了 我都快憋死了
You and Leslie?
你和Leslie?
In the paintball shed! Twice!
在彩弹小棚里! 还两次呢!
Is that why you didn't cover our escape
and let us get cut down like animals?
这就是你没有掩护我们出逃
让我们任人宰割的原因?
Oh, yeah, sorry about that.
噢 没错 真是抱歉
My good man, dereliction of duty in the
face of the enemy is a court-martial offense.
我的老兄 在敌人面前玩忽职守
可是要被送上军事法庭的
Court-martial, schmort-martial, Leslie Winkle
is the fifth girl I've ever had sex with.
军事法庭也好 笨蛋法庭也罢
Leslie Winkle是我上的第五个女人
I mean, for free.
我是说 不要钱的那种
And plus, you got a rapid prototyper.
别忘了 你还得到了快速原型机
That's an expensive
piece of equipment, dude.
老兄 那玩意儿可不便宜
And the rest of us have had
our budgets cut to the bone.
而我们的预算经费被剥削了
Okay, one way to look at this is
that I'm getting new equipment,
看起来好像是我得到了新的仪器
and you're not, and that's unfair.
而你们没有 这很不公平
But a better way to look at this is that I'm
getting sex and you're not, and that's delightful.
但你们换个角度看看就是
我和别人上床而你们没有 多高兴
The whole thing froze. I
don't know what happened.
不知道怎么搞的 完全死机了
Calm down. We'll figure it out.
冷静点 会有办法的
How can I calm down? I'm gonna
lose my whole shopping cart.
我要怎么冷静?
我购物车里的所有东西都没了
That's three hours of picking
out shoes just shot to hell.
我花了三个小时选的鞋子就这么没了
- Hello, Penny.
- Hello, Sheldon.
- 你好 Penny
- 你好 Sheldon
You're in my spot.
你占了我的座
Are you planning on sitting here?
你打算坐在这儿?
No, I'm going to the comic book store.
没有 我打算去漫画书店
Then what difference does it make?
那我坐这儿怎么了?
- What difference does it make?
- Here we go.
- 你坐这儿怎么了?
- 又来了
That is my spot.
那是我的座
In an ever-changing world, it
is a single point of consistency.
在这个不断变化的世界中
那是唯一一个连续点
If my life were expressed as a function on a
four-dimensional Cartesian coordinate system,
如果将我的人生比作
四维笛卡尔坐标系里的一个函数
that spot at the moment I first sat
on it would be zero-zero-zero-zero.
在我第一次坐上那儿的时候
那个座的坐标就是(0,0,0,0)
What?
啥意思?
Don't sit in his spot.
别坐他的地儿
Fine. Happy?
好吧 开心了?
I'm not unhappy.
我没不开心呀
Boy, I love him, but he
is one serious waadoodle.
我爱他 但他实在怪里怪气
Okay, that should do it.
好了 应该成了
Oh, thank you. You are a lifesaver.
哦 谢谢 救了我的命
That's a lot of shoes you ordered.
你还真定了不少鞋啊
Yeah, you know the sad
thing is, it's really not.
可悲的是啥知道不 这根本不算多
Ooh, is thisne of those paintball guns?
哦 这就是那彩弹枪?
Yeah. You ought to come
out with us sometime.
是啊 找时间一起来玩呗
Oh, no, thanks. I'm from Nebraska.
哦 不 谢了 我是内布拉斯加州人
When we shoot things, it's because we want to
eat them or make them leave our boyfriends alone.
我们开枪 要么是要吃那玩意
要么就是让她们离我们男友远点
Boy, your heart's racing. I
must've really gotten you going.
哦 你心跳很快啊 我还真有两下子呢
Well, it's partly you, partly
my transient idiopaic arrhythmia.
你只是一部分原因
我有短暂自发性心律不齐
Sexy.
性感呦
Can I assume that you likewise
found the experience...
我可不可以说你也觉得这过程...
Satisfactory?
很满足?
That wasn't quite the word I was looking
for, but sure, I'll do this pass-fail.
我不是想用这个词
不过是的 过与不过来衡量蛮好
Hey, are you enjoying
that prototyper I got you?
嘿 那原型机用着还不错吧?
Oh, it's great.
哦 好极了
Everybody in the Engineering
Department is eating their hearts out.
工程部的人眼馋得
哈喇子都快流出来了
Isn't it nice when your good
fortune makes others miserable?
你这么好命让别人惨兮兮的
感觉不错吧?
You know, most people don't get that.
要知道 有些人想不通
Howard, I'm home!
Howard 我回来了!
Oh, great.
这下好了
Book club was cancelled!
读书会取消了!
That thing on Phyllis's
neck opened up again!
Phyllis脖子上那玩意又爆开了!
I'm busy, Ma!
我忙着呢 妈!
Too busy to help your
mother with her zipper?
忙的没工夫帮你老妈拉拉链了?
Don't come in, Ma!
别进来 妈!
Why not?
为啥不?
He's got company!
有人在呢!
Oh, there's the arrhythmia.
哦 心律不齐了
Is she Jewish?
是犹太人不?
- Are you Jewish?
- No.
- 你是犹太人吗?
- 不是
Yes!
是!
Okay, then you kids have fun!
那你们好好玩吧!
Use protection!
注意防护!
You think he'll notice?
他会发现不?
There's a chance.
有可能吧
Oh, what are we gonna do?
我们怎么办呀?
We?
我们?
No, no, you had your chance to be
"we" for, like, a year and a half now.
不 不 不 一年半啊
你本有机会选择"我们"的
Right now, you are "you,"
and you are screwed.
现在呢 你就是"你" 你完蛋了
Why do we have to tell him I did it?
干嘛非要告诉他是我干的?
Well, we're not gonna tell him I did it.
反正不会说是我干的
Okay, okay, how about this?
好了 好了 看这样行不?
We tell him somebody broke in.
我们告诉他有人闯进来过
Just to shoot the couch
with a paintball gun?
就为了用彩弹枪喷沙发?
I'm sorry, Iuy it. All
those people are on drugs.
抱歉 我就会信 嗑药的人啥事不干
We could him they wanted the couch
to stay away from their boyfriend.
可以跟他说他们想让
沙发离他们男朋友远点
Okay, fine. What if
we just flip it over?
这样吧 干脆翻过来呢?
There. Looks fine, right?
好了 看着还行 是吧?
Mm, butt print. There's
no discernible butt print.
屁股印记 上面没有屁股印记啊
Oh, come on.
哦 好了啦
There, butt print.
瞧 屁股
It's too small and too... perfect.
太小太...完美了
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- 谢谢
- 不客气
Act normal.
正常点
Sheldon!
How was the comic book store?
漫画书店怎么样啊?
Fine. e new issue of Flash is out.
挺好 新一期的闪电侠出了
Great, great. Did you walk the
whole way? It's a little chilly.
真好 真好 你走着去的? 天有点冷啊
Koothrappali picked me up.
Koothrappali让我搭车了
Isn't that terrific?
真棒呀
He is such a good friend.
他真是个好朋友
You know what the best
thing about friends is?
你知道做朋友最好的一点是什么吗?
They don't talk incessantly
for no particular reason.
不会无缘无故说个没完
No, no, friends forgive
the little things.
不 不 朋友不会计较小事
You know, I gotta go
home and wash my hair.
那啥 我回家洗头去哈
Don't you dare, missy.
想都别想 小姐
Hello, fastest man alive.
你好 现存速度最快的人
Want to see me read
your entire comic book?
想看我读你整本漫画书不?
Want to see it again?
想再看一遍不?
Something's wrong.
有问题
What do you mean?
啥意思?
I'm not sure.
说不清
It doesn't feel right.
就是感觉不对
I don't know what you're talking about.
不知道你在说些什么
Oh, that. Penny did that.
哦 那个啊 Penny弄的
Excuse me.
借过
Why don't you just
eat in your desk chair?
坐写字椅那吃不就好了嘛
Why don't I just eat in my desk chair?
坐写字椅那吃不就好了嘛?
Here we go.
开始了
That is my desk chair.
That is where I work.
那是我写字椅 是我工作的地方
I don't eat in my desk chair
and I don't work in my spot.
我不在写字椅那吃东西
不在我的位置上工作
I work in my desk chair
and eat in my spot.
而是在写字椅工作
在我的位置上吃饭
Wackadoodle.
怪里怪气
You know, there's kind of an
obvious solution here. Get up.
要知道 有个很容易的解决办法 起来
There. Problem solved.
好了 解决
Nobody cares where you're
going to sit. You're not crazy.
没人在乎你坐哪 你又不是疯子
Excuse me, but the
problem is not solved.
抱歉 但问题没解决啊
If your head had been accidentally amputated,
and we transplanted a dog's head in its place,
要是你的脑袋意外被割掉了
我们把狗脑袋给你移植过去
would that be "problem solved"?
你说"问题解决"了不?
If it were your head, it would be.
要是你的脑袋 我看成
Sheldon, I am really, really
sorry, but it's only for a week.
Sheldon 我十分十分抱歉 但就一周嘛
Can't you be a little bit flexible?
你就将就点不行吗?
Yeah, sorry. I didn't
really think that through.
哦 对不起 我没想好就开口了
You claimed it's going to be a week,
but I have no faith in your dry cleaner.
你说一周就行 但我信不过你那干洗工
Why not?
为什么?
Did you notice the sign on his counter?
你注意到他柜台上的招牌没?
He's not a full-time dry cleaner.
他不是专职干洗工
He also makes keys.
他还是个配钥匙的
Oh, for God's sake, Sheldon.
看在老天的份上 Sheldon
Focus is important.
办事专注很重要的
Was Michael DeBakey a wedding
planner in between heart transplants?
心脏移植专家麦可・德贝基
会兼职做婚礼策划员吗?
Did Alexander Fleming
moonlight as a hairdresser?
细菌学家亚历山大・弗莱明
会兼做美发师吗?
"Thanks for discovering penicillin.
Now how about we try a bouffant?"
"感谢你发现了青霉素
现在做个蓬松波浪发型怎样?"
Ooh, looks like I'm
gonna have sex tonight.
看来我今晚要嘿咻了
Hey, baby...
宝贝你好...
His right hand is calling him?
他的右手给他打电话了?
No, it's Leslie Winkle.
It's a long story.
不是啦 是Leslie Winkle 说来话长
I'll pick you up in ten minutes.
我十分钟后去接你
Gentlemen, adieu.
先生们 再会
I thought we were going
to play Halo tonight.
我们还得一起玩光晕呢
What am I supposed to do, Leonard?
你说我该怎么做 Leonard?
There's a woman out there
anxious to have sex with me.
有个女人正饥渴地盼望和我上床呢
You understand, right?
你肯定能理解 对吧?
No. Not at all.
不 完全不能
Nevertheless, I must depart.
不管怎样 我得出发了
By the way, did I tell you?
对了 我告诉过你没有?
Leslie pulled some strings and got me on the research
trip to Geneva to check out the CERN Supercollider.
由于Leslie暗箱操作 我能去日内瓦的
欧洲物理研究所参观超级超导对撞机了
That's not fair. You're
not even a physicist.
这不公平 你又不是物理学家
Okay, there are two ways
of looking at this...
你可以换个角度看...
- Get out.
- Bye.
- 出去!
- 拜拜
You're improving.
你有进步了
Thank you. It helps when I get
to practice with a real woman.
谢谢 和真正的女人在一起进步快
Hey, listen. Saturday my
sister's getting married.
嘿 我姐姐周六要结婚了
I-I want you to come
with me. It's black tie.
我想你跟我一起去 是半正式场合
Yeah, gee, I'd really rather not.
我还真不太想去
Why not?
为什么?
When I go to weddings, it's
to scam on chunky bridesmaids.
我去婚礼 都是去骗胖胖的伴娘的
I don't know what I
would do with a date.
不知道带了伴该干点啥
Oh, all right. I understand.
哦 好吧 能理解
Thanks.
谢谢
Hey, I'm really sorry
about that Geneva trip.
日内瓦的事很抱歉
What about it?
怎么了?
Oh, didn't you hear?
你没听说?
I had to reduce the number of people
going, and you didn't make the cut.
要削减出行的人数 你被选下来了
When did that haen?
啥时候的事?
About 12 seconds ago.
大概12秒之前吧
Well, hold on. Are you saying if I don't
go to the wedding, I can't go to Geneva?
等等 你是说我不去婚礼
就去不了日内瓦?
Actually, I'm trying not to say it.
我就是不想说那么明白嘛
Okay, I'm sorry, but that
makes me a little uncomfortable.
好吧 抱歉 但我觉得有点不自在
How so?
怎么会?
Because it's like you're controlling me
with new equipment and research trips.
感觉你在用新仪器和外出调研控制我
Well, if I weren't controlling you with new equipment
and research trips, then I'd be uncomfortable.
要是我不用新仪器和外出调研控制你
就该换我不自在了
How so?
怎么会?
'Cause then we'd be in, like, a real
relationship with feelings and all that crap.
因为那样的话 我们就好像真正在交往了
So, bottom line, I'm just a
bought-and-paid-for sex toy.
那么 说到底 我就是你摆弄的嘿咻玩偶
No. No, noat all. You're also arm candy.
不 才不是 你还是个好伴儿
So? What do you think?
怎样? 你怎么想?
Hey, Ma, you got to rent me a tux!
嘿 妈 帮我租件礼服!
Right now?
现在?
What kind of sex are
you having up there?
你们在上面玩啥花样呢?
Why are you crouching there?
你干嘛蹲在这?
This is my spot.
这是我的地儿啊
Where else am I supposed to crouch?
我还能蹲哪?
I don't know. Texas?
不知道 德州?
Here you go. Fresh from
the cleaners, good as new.
来咯 刚拿回来的 焕然一新
Really? Great. Sheldon,
look. Good as new.
真的啊? 太好了 Sheldon
看看 跟新的一样
From that key maker, I highly doubt it.
那配钥匙的那儿 不敢信
Come on, Sheldon. Just give it a try.
好了啦 Sheldon 试试看嘛
All right.
好吧
There, nice and comfy
cozy. Zero, zero, zero.
好了 舒适 惬意 安逸 0 0 0
There's one more zero.
少了个0
You forgot the time parameter.
你把时间参数忘了
Sit on the damn couch.
坐你的沙发吧
Nope.
不对
What do you mean, "nope"?
What's wrong with it?
啥意思啊"不对"? 有什么问题?
Nothing, it's what's wrong with him.
没问题 有问题的是他
- It's exactly the same...
- Penny, Penny,
- 完全是同一...
- Penny Penny
I think I know what to do.
我想我知道该怎么办了
Sheldon, I have some bad news.
Sheldon 我有坏消息
More?
还有啊?
I'm afraid so.
恐怕是的
You know the cashew chicken
I get you Monday nights?
记得每周一晚上我给你买的腰果鸡丁吗?
Yes. From Szechuan Palace.
是的 川府菜馆买的嘛
Szechuan Palace closed two years ago.
川府菜馆两年前就关门了
What? Whe did my cashew
chicken come from?
什么? 那我的腰果鸡丁哪来的?
Golden Dragon.
金龙餐馆
No.
不
No, this isn't right.
不 这可不对啊
Our food always comes in
Szechuan Palace containers.
我们的菜一直是用川府的餐盒装的
Yeah, well, before they went out of
business, I bought 4,000 containers.
他们关门前 我买了4000个餐盒
I keep them in the trunk of my car.
放在我车的后备箱里
But... Oh, this changes everything.
但...一切都变了
I thought that might take
his mind off the cushion.
我觉得可以让他忘了垫子的事
What's real? What isn't? How can I know?
什么是真的? 什么不是? 我怎么知道?
You did make that up, right?
你瞎编的 是吧?
Oh, God, I wish I had.
哦 老天 我倒希望是
- Leonard?
- Yeah, buddy?
- 嗯 伙计?
I still don't like this cushion.
我还是不喜欢这垫子
ll, Penny, thank you for coming.
好了 首先 Penny 谢谢你能来
Thanks for the shoes.
鞋谢你了
Penny is an amazing shot. I think we
have a real chance to win this week.
Penny是神枪手 我看这周我们赢面很大
- What's the plan?
- Okay. Now, we all run out.
- 计划呢?
- 这样 现在 我们都跑出去
Sheldon and I will cut to
the left behind these trees.
Sheldon和我切到左边树后面
Raj, Howard and Leslie flank
to the right behind the rocks.
Raj Howard和Leslie守在右侧石头后
Then we'll all have a great view as Penny
runs out and kills everyone else in sight.
Penny出来将视线中的敌人一举歼灭时
我们将有非常好的视线
Just one thing before we start.
开战前还有一件事
What is it, Sheldon?
什么事 Sheldon?
What the hell?
搞什么啊?
That was for my cushion.
这下是为了我的垫子
Sheldon, Penny was our only hope.
Sheldon Penny是我们唯一的希望
I'm sorry, Leonard. But revenge
is a dish best served cold.
抱歉 Leonard 但报仇就要冷不及防
Screw that.
去你的
She can't shoot me. She's dead.
她不能打我的 她死了呀
He's right. You can't.
他说的对 你不能开枪
Well, if we're going to
descend into anarchy...
要是真想混乱下去的话...
Okay, see you.
好吧 再见
Where are you going?
你们去哪?
Surrender, then Denny's.
投降 然后去Denny's餐馆吃饭
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=-
sync:咔肉肉
天才理论传
第二季 第16集 完